# **Artem Pakhomov**

## Lead PHP Developer from Kyiv, Ukraine

Phone: +380 (50) 027-93-00
Email: setnemo@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/setnemo Other Social Media: @setnemo



I have been working in the web industry for the past seven years. I'm writing a code according to SOLID, KISS, YAGNI, DRY. I'm publishing all my pet projects on Github as I adore open source. I'm a backend developer, and I fancy creating telegram bots. I began studying to play piano during the lockdown. This CV was created on PHP with GitHub Actions as I can't live without automation. I am married, have 2 kids and 3 cats. I like to spend time with my family, read books, watch TV series.

#### **Technologies**

PHP: OOP, SOLID, REST, TDD, PHPDoc, PSR, MVC, Composer, Laravel

DB and Brokers: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, RabbitMQ

Tests: PHPUnit, Codeception

Git: understand rebase, reflog, squash, cherry-pick, soft/hard reset, etc

Unix: used ArchLinux, Debian, Mint, Ubuntu, macOS, vim, grep, sed, awk, ssh, etc

Containers: docker, k8s

Dev environment: nginx/docker, Postman, PHPStorm, xDebug, Makefile

#### **Experience**

#### Senior PHP Developer at Social Media (NDA) Remote, Ukraine - 04/2022 - Present

Project details are prohibited by non-disclosure agreement

#### Lead PHP Developer at Blockster Kyiv, Ukraine - 04/2021 - 03/2022 ~1 year

- I was implemented the way which was provided migration from old legacy code (white label) to the modern application (Laravel)
- I was implemented a metrics (raw data to Postgres, aggregated to Prometheus) and an experiment (for A/B testing on backend) system, which provides more understanding about user experience with our product
- I was mentored the backend developers team (~5 backend) and helped other teams with processes, cross-team developing, sharing knowledge
- I was provided changes for processes: move gitlab issues to Jira (create automation), create workflows for all colleagues(design/development/ga), taught colleagues use it.
- I was created some automation for a lot of things, which made more clearly and useful decomposition/developing/testing/duty flow

#### PHP Developer at airSlate Inc Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2019 - 04/2021 ~2 years

- I wrote code with tests and documentation, made code review
- I deployed on dev/rc for testing, deployed releases on production
- I configured alert rules and checking the cause of alerts, working with metrics (tech and business)

#### PHP Developer at Wallet Factory Kyiv, Ukraine - 01/2019 - 05/2019 ~6 months

- Back-end development for a Fin-tech mobile application.
- PHP 7+, OpenSSL, payments API integrations
- API integrations for sales/discounting etc

#### PHP Developer at MakeTop Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2015 - 12/2018 ~3,5 years

- I wrote implementation for search engine optimization
- I was working with popular CMS and self-hosted websites.

#### Education

#### Software Architect UNIT Factory, Kyiv - 09/2017 - 11/2018

I was one of 5 students with the best marks in UNIT Factory (course 2017), I completed the 3-year program (Ecole 42, France) in 1 year. UNIT Factory StudHub. Volunteering in Exam. Event organization. Meet-up organization.

#### Pet projects

#### Repeat Word Bot https://t.me/RepeatWordBot

- Telegram bo which help you revise new English words and learn pronunciation
- PHP, Doctrine, MySQL, Redis, Codeception, Docker, GitHub Actions

### Currencies in UA Bot https://t.me/CurrencyUA bot

- · Currency conversion (inline) for Ukraine
- PHP, MySQL, Redis, Api integrations, Docker

#### Asterios RB bot https://github.com/setnemo/asterios-bot

- Bot that helps more than 2000 players from Asterios Lineage II Server
- PHP, MySQL, Redis, Codeception, Docker, Github Actions

### Begone github.com/setnemo/bygone

- Archive your old repositories to one repo (git history included) with Github Actions
- bash, git, Github Actions

#### Languages

English - Professional proficiency, (fluent intermediate)

Ukrainian - Native or bilingual proficiency

# Volunteer experience

### SuperGrandchildren at Happy Lunch

CO "Lifelover" happyold.com.ua

Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2019 - 03/2020

#### Military Volonteer at russian-Ukrainian War'22

Lviv, Ukraine - 03/2022 - 09/2022

Raised donates more than \$30,000 for Kevlar helmets, a night vision scope, tactical goggles and other equipment, medical support for a combat engineers battery of the Ukrainian Armed Forces from Donetska region